Cook, Alice Papers /3012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series Series VII: Publications and Writings
  - Sub-Series A. Publications
    - Cook, Alice H., 1972 (Box 104, Folder 42)
      Rev. of Nazis and Workers: National Socialist Appeals to German Labor, by Max H. Kele. Tel Aviv. November, 1972
    - Cook, Alice H., 1976 (Box 104, Folder 42)
      Rev. of Time of Transition: The Growth of Families Headed by Women, by Heather L. Ross and Isabel V. Sawhill. Monthly Labor Review. September 1976.
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 42)
      Rev. of Japanese Urbanism: Industry and Politics in Kariya, by Gary D. Allinson. NY: Cornell Univesity
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 42)
      Rev. of The Politics of Labor in Japan, by Ehud Harari. Journal of Asian Studies. 713-715
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 42)
      Rev. of Professors, Unions and American Higher Education, by Everett Carl Ladd Jr., and Antibias Regulation of Universities: Faculty Problems and their Solutions, by Richard A. Lester. ILR Review. October.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1961 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      AHC Publications. January 1961
    - Cook, Alice H., 1961 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of CIO Challenge to the AFL: A History of the Labor Movement, 1935-1941, by Walter Galenson. ILR Review. January 1961.
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of A History of American Labor, by Joseph G. Rayback. ILR Review.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1971 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of Japanese Blue Collar: The Changing Tradition, by Robert E. Cole. Monthly Labor Report. 1971
    - Cook, Alice H., 1962 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of European Unity and the Trade Union Movements, by R. Colin Beever. ILR Review. April, 1962. 430-431
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of Professions and Professionalization, by J.A. Jackson. ILR Review.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1970 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of The Japanese Employee, Robert J. Ballon ed. ILR Review. October 1970. 115-116.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1966 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of The Practice of Local Union Leadership: A Study of Five Local Unions, by Robert W. Miller, Frederick A. Zeller, et al. ILR Review. July 1966. 628-629.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1971 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of United Federation of Teachers: A Case Study of the UFT, by Stephan Cole. ILR Review. January 1971
    - Cook, Alice H., 1970 (Box 104, Folder 43)
      Rev. of The Unionization of Teachers: A Case Study of the UFT, by Stephen Cole. ILR Review. 1970
    - Cook, Alice H., 1968 (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of American Unions: Structure, Government and Politics, by John Barbash, and The Unions: Structure, Development and Management, by Martin Estey, and The Local Union, by Leonard R. Sayles and George Strauss. ILR Review. July 1968. 620-622.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1964 (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of The Rank and File Leader, by Sidney M. Peck. ILR Review. October 1964
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of The Urbanization of Japanese Labor, 1868-1955, by Thomas Wilkinson. Labor History
    - Cook, Alice H., 1960 (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of Labor Unions and Public Policy, by Edward H. Chamberlain, Philip D. Bradley, et al. ILR Review. January 1960.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1958 (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of Britons in American Labor: A History of the Influence of the United Kingdom Immigrants on American Labor, 1820-1914, by Clifton K. Yearly. ILR Review. October 8, 1958.
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of American Labor Unions and Politics, 1900-1918, by Marc Karson
    - Cook, Alice H., 1957 (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of Nine Lives for Labor, by Richard Kelly. ILR Review. January 1957. 326.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1958 (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of The A.F of L. in the Time of Gompers, by Philip Taft. ILR Review. January 1958.
    - Cook, Alice H. (Box 104, Folder 44)
      Rev. of The Political Imperative: The Corporate Character of Unions, by Gus Tyler. The Monthly Labor Review.
    - Klein-low, Dr. Stella. "The Working Mother.", 1976 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of (I think) The Working Mother: A Survey of Problems and Programs in Nine Countries, by Alice H. Cook. Sozialistische Erziehung. June 1976. (The Review is in German, I think)
    - Rev. of The Working Mother (Die arbeitende Mutter): Eine Ubersicht iiber Probleme und Programme in neun Landern, by Alice Cook, 1975 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Die Zuhumft. 1975. 23-24. (The review is in German)
    - Berg, Anne-Marie., 1987 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of Women and Trade Unions in Eleven Industrial Countries, by Alice Cook, Women and Trade Unions in Eleven Industrial Countries, by Alice Cook, Val R. Lorwin et al. Economic and Industrial Democracy: An International Journal. Vol. 8, No. 2. May 1987.
    - Rev. of Women and Trade Unions in Eleven Industrial Countries, by Alice Cook, Arlene Kaplan Daniels, et al. (Box 104, Folder 45)
      25-27
    - Salaff, Janet W., 1982 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, By Alice H. Cook. ILR Review. October 1982.
    - Bernard, Jessie. "New Non-fiction.", 1984 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of Women and Trade Unions in Eleven Industrialized Countries, Alice Cook, Val R. Lorwin, et al eds. New Directions for Women. September/October 1984.
    - Kassell, Paula. "Equal Pay.", 1984 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      New Directions for Women. September/October 1984.
    - Bilson, Beth., 1990 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of Women Workers in Fifteen Countries: Essays in Honor of Alice Hanson Cook, Jennie Farley ed. Canadian Journal of Women and the Law, Vol. 4. 1990. 335-338.
    - Eaton, Susan C. "Women and Unions: Reluctant Partners, Unrealized Potential.", 1994 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of Woman and Unions: Forging a Partnership, by Dorothy Sue Cobble, and The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions, by Alice H. Cook. Contemporary Sociology, Vol. 23, No. 2. March, 1994.
    - Rev. of Women and the Trade Unions in Eleven Industrialized Countries, by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin, et al., 1987 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Economic and Industrial Democracy. May, 1987.
    - Rev. of Working Women in Japan, by Alice H. Cook and Hiroko Hayashi, 1983 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      California Western International Law Journal, Vol. 13. No. 3. Summer, 1983. 532.
    - Pharr, Susan J., 1982 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of Working Women in Japan, by Alice H. Cook and Hiroko Hayashi. Journal of Asian Studies. February 1982
    - Mini, Anne A., 1995 (Box 104, Folder 45)
      Rev. of The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions, by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin et al. Women and Politics. Vol. 15, No. 3. 1995.
    - Rev. of The Working Mother: A Survey of Problems and Programs in Nine Countries, by Alice H. Cook. (Box 104, Folder 45)
      The Spokeswoman. June 15
    - Oakley, Ann., 1976 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Rev. of The Working Mother: A Survey of Problems and Programs in Nine Countries, by Alice H. Cook. Women Speaking. October/December 1976. 23.
    - Rev. of The Working Mother: A Survey of Problems and Programs in Nine Countries, by Alice H. Cook., 1975 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Womanpower: Employers Monthly Report on Equal Opportunity for Women. May 1975. 6.
    - Rev. of Adult Education in Citizenship in Postwar Germany, by Alice Hanson Cook., 1954 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      National University Extension Association Bulletin. Vol. 19, No. 10. June 1954.
    - Rev. of Labor's Role in Community Affairs- A Handbook for Union Committees, by Mrs. Alice H. Cook., 1956 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Trends in Personal Relations. January 11, 1956.
    - Holden, Karen. Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi, 1982 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Sex Roles. Vol. 8, No. 2. 1982.
    - Rawski, Evelyn S. Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Library Journal. September
    - Cook, Alice. "Working the Double Day.", 1988 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Rev. of More Equal than Others: Women and Men in Dual-Career Marriages, by Rosanna Hertz, and Managing Success: High-Echelon Careers and Motherhood, by Aasta Lubin, and Remaking Motherhood: How Working Mothers are Shaping Our Children's Future, by Anita Shreve, and Spouse, Parent, Worker: On Gender and Multiple Roles, Faye J Crosby, ed., and Families and Work, Naomi Gerstel and Harriet Engel Gross eds., and Women, Households, and the Economy, Lourdes Beneria and Catharine Stimpson eds. The Women's Review of Books. Vol 6, No. 1. October 1988.
    - Glenn, Evelyn Nakano., 1981 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi. Contemporary Sociology. Vol. 10, No. 6. November 1981
    - Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi, 1980 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      International Journal of Manpower. 1980.
    - Rev. of Working Women in Japan, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi, 1981-1982 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      The Japan Foundation Newsletter. Vol. 9, No. 5. December 1981-January 1982. 14.
    - Lavigne, Marie., 1981 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Rev. of The Working Mother: A Survey of Problems and Programs in Nine Countries, by Alice H. Cook. Relations Industrielles. Vol. 36, No. 2. 1981. (Review is in French, translation provided on a separate sheet)
    - Rev. of The Working Mother: A Survey of Problems and Programs in Nine Countries, by Alice H. Cook., 1975 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Labor. Vol. 57, No. 16. August 30, 1975. 6.
    - Rev. of The Working Mother: A Survey of Problems and Programs in Nine Countries, by Alice H. Cook., 1975 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Vertical File Index. March 1975. 9.
    - Cook, Alice H. "Working Women- European experience and American Need.", 1977 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Section from American Women Workers in A Full Emploment Economy. Publication Notice. "Study on the Role of American Women Workers in a Full Employment Economy." Joint Economic Committee Press Release. Congress of the United States. 95th Congress. September 16, 1977.
    - Boatman, Robin Misner., 1982 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi. Monthly Labor Review. April 1982.
    - "Additional Reading.", 1983 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Natural History. February 1983
    - Harris, Howard., 1983 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi. Labor Studies Journal. Spring 1983.
    - Cook, Alice H., 1980 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions. 1980. (first two pages)
    - Waltner, Ann., 1981 (Box 104, Folder 46)
      Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance, and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, and Hiroko Hayashi. Asia Record. May 1981.
    - Cook, Alice C. Untitled., 1966 (Box 104, Folder 47)
      The American Labor Review. August 1966.
    - Rev. of The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions, by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin et al., 1993 (Box 104, Folder 48)
      Journal of Economic Literature. June 1993.
    - Rose, Sonya O., 1995 (Box 104, Folder 48)
      Rev. of Threads of Solidarity: Women in South African Industry, 1900-1980, by Iris Berger, and The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions, by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin et al., and Sweatshop Strife: Class, Ethnicity, and Gender in the Jewish Labour Movement of Toronto, 1900-1939, by Ruth A. Frager, and Maid in the U.S.A, by Sharon Hartman Strom, and Working Women of Collar City: Gender, Class and Community in Troy, 1864-86, by Carole Turbin, and Factory Daughters: Gender, Household Dynamics, and Rural Industrialization, by Diane Lauren Wolf. Signs. Winter 1995. 448-455.
    - Blackburn, Shelia., 1994 (Box 104, Folder 48)
      Rev. of The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions, by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin et al. Labour History Review. Vol. 59, No. 1. Spring 1994. 60-62.
    - Engerman, Stanley L. The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions, by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin et al. (Box 104, Folder 48)
      Labor History. 534-535.
    - American Library Association., 1993 (Box 104, Folder 48)
      Rev. of The Most Difficult Revolution: Women and Trade Unions, by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin et al. Choice. June 1993.
    - Higa, Lori R. "EEO Around the World.", 1981 (Box 104, Folder 49)
      Rev. of Working Women in Japan: Discrimination, Resistance and Reform, by Alice H. Cook, & Hiroko Hayashi. Forum. March 1981. 36-37
    - ILR Research at Cornell., 1989 (Box 104, Folder 49)
      Winter 1989
    - Gruenberg, Craig. "Labor expert sees sex bias on faculty.", 1981 (Box 104, Folder 49)
      Honolulu Advertiser. Saturday March 14, 1981. B- 3.
    - Biographical Sketches (Box 104, Folder 50)
      Lists of People to notify about the Publishing of Alice Cook's Various books
    - "United States of America Economic Cooperation Administration- Special Mission to Austria.", 1950 (Box 104, Folder 51)
      Written in German, I think
    - Paper on the voting in Austria in the late 1940s, presumably by Alice Cook (Box 104, Folder 51)
    - Cook, Alice?. "Methods in the US." (Box 104, Folder 51)
    - Cook, Alice?. "Die Methodik Der Arbeitbildung." (Box 104, Folder 51)
    - Cook, Alice?. "Workers Education." (Box 104, Folder 51)
    - Outline and Notes to an Unidentified Manuscript (Box 104, Folder 52)
    - Revisions?, Notes?, or Comments? on "Participation and Mass Apathy in Associations," by Bernard Barber. (Box 104, Folder 53)
      Chapter in Studies in Leadership, by Alvin Gouldner.
    - Drafts of Three Untitled papers, presumably written by Alice Cook (Box 104, Folder 54)
    - Notes (Box 104, Folder 55)
    - Cook, Alice H. "Zwei Jahre deutsch-amerikanische Zusammenarbeit Eine Ruckschau.", 1976 (Box 104, Folder 55)
  - Sub-Series B. Speeches
    - Cook, Alice H. Address., 1959 (Box 105, Folder 1)
      Saratoga Springs Conference. NY: 1959
    - Cook, Alice H. Law Affected States: Non-profit Agencies, 1972 (Box 105, Folder 2)
      American Jewish Congress. 1972.
    - Cook, Alice H. Address., 1977 (Box 105, Folder 3)
      Job Loss Seminar. 1977
    - Summary of an interview between Jill Strickland and Alice Cook about "Working Mothers Around the World.", 1978 (Box 105, Folder 4)
      29- Jun-78
    - Cook, Alice H. The Way it Was (Box 105, Folder 4)
      Union Maids, ILR Conference Center. July 11.
    - Cook, Alice H. Changes in Women's Status, 1978 (Box 105, Folder 4)
      April 21, 1978.
    - Cook, Alice H. Reentry Programs for Women: An International Comparison, 1978 (Box 105, Folder 4)
      Aspen-Berlin Seminar. September 25- 29, 1978
    - Cook, Alice H. Social Policy and the Working Mother., 1978 (Box 105, Folder 4)
      National Council on Family, Philadelphia PA. October 20, 1978.
    - Cook, Alice H. Women and Unions: Cause for Celebration., 1981 (Box 105, Folder 5)
      Gold's Class. November 6, 1981.
    - Cook, Alice H. Women and the American Labor Movement, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 5)
      Rutgers. October 6, 1981.
    - Cook, Alice H. Women and Trade Unions: A Comparative View, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 5)
      University of Illinois. April 1981.
    - Cook, Alice H. Be Prepared for Change, 1982 (Box 105, Folder 6)
      Utica, NY. September 20, 1982.
    - Cook, Alice H. Institutional Commitment to AA., 1983 (Box 105, Folder 7)
      U.H., Honolulu. March 14, 1983.
    - Cook, Alice H. A Topical Outline for a Statement on the Japan Film on Management., 1983 (Box 105, Folder 7)
      1-Nov-83
    - Cook, Alice H. Labor Relations and the Role of Women, 1983 (Box 105, Folder 7)
      Nickum. November 15, 1983.
    - Cook, Alice H. Outline of an Address on Comparable Worth, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 8)
      Oregon. 1984.
    - Cook, Alice H. Women and Trade Unions in Industrialized Countries. Harvard/Wellesley., 1984 (Box 105, Folder 8)
      12-Apr-84
    - Cook, Alice H. Problems in Comparable Worth, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. US Experience in Comparable Worth, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
      Toronto. September 14, 1985.
    - Cook, Alice H. Pay Equity, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. Overview of Comparable Worth Initiatives: Public Sector. Conference on Women and Work, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
      Boston MA. November 8, 1985
    - Cook, Alice H. Outline of and Address, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. Comparable Worth, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. Distinction Between Male and Female Wages- History, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. History of Comparable Worth., 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
      Minnesota Conference. Minnesota. October 18, 1985.
    - Cook, Alice H. Union Activity, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. Notes on Comparable Worth, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
      Cornell Libraries. December 12, 1985.
    - Cook, Alice H. Comparable Worth, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. Civil Liberties Union, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Cook, Alice H. Pay Equity/Comparable Worth, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 10)
      Carol Bohmer's Class. November 3, 1986.
    - Cook, Alice H. Women in Academe: What Can We do to Remedy Their Situation?, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 10)
      UPHA, Honolulu Hawaii. March 1986
    - Cook, Alice H. Address, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 10)
      Peterborough. August 10, 1986
    - Cook, Alice H. Comparable Worth: The Problems of Implementation, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 10)
      Women's Network Meeting. Washington D.C. April 15, 1986
    - Cook, Alice H. Work and Family: An Overview of Theories and Problems, 1987 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Cook, Alice H. Family and Work: Challenges to Labor, Management and Government., 1987 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      Canadian Industrial Research Association. McMaster University. June 5, 1987.
    - Cook, Alice H. Women in a Man's World., 1987 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      Canadian Flight Attendants. October 24, 1987.
    - Cook, Alice H. Address., 1987 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      International Team. ILR Extension. October 1, 1987.
    - Cook, Alice H. Work and Family., 1987 (Box 105, Folder 11)
      Reunion. June 12, 1987
    - Cook, Alice H. Work and Family: Conflict or Accommodation?, 1988 (Box 105, Folder 12)
      The Hauge. January 21, 1988.
    - Cook, Alice H. Unions: Are They Keeping Up With Women?, 1988 (Box 105, Folder 12)
      Hofstra- District 65. April 30, 1988.
    - Cook, Alice H. Economic Crises Household Survival Strategies and Women's Work., 1988 (Box 105, Folder 12)
      Program on International Development and Women. Cornell University, Ithaca NY. September 5, 1988
    - Cook, Alice H. Address., 1988 (Box 105, Folder 12)
      Haus Buchenried. October 4-8, 1988. In German
    - Cook, Alice H. Comparable Worth/Pay Equity., 1988 (Box 105, Folder 12)
      Business and Professional Women. Ithaca, NY. November 10, 1988, and November 28, 1988 in Watkins Glen.
    - Cook, Alice H. Labor, Management and Family Problems., 1989 (Box 105, Folder 13)
      25-Jul-89
    - Cook, Alice H. How the Changing Student Body Changed Cornell, 1989 (Box 105, Folder 13)
      Farley Class. November 27, 1989.
    - Cook, Alice H. Report on the Status of Comparable Worth and Other Issues of Interest to Working Women., 1989 (Box 105, Folder 13)
      Hawaii State Commission on the Status of Women. January 17, 1989.
    - Cook, Alice H. Family Equality and Alternative Work Schedules., 1989 (Box 105, Folder 13)
      Work Schedules: Work and Family Seminar. December 1, 1989.
    - Cook, Alice H. Employer Responsibility: Current Issues and Concerns, 1989 (Box 105, Folder 13)
      Netter Seminar. September 24, 1989
    - Cook, Alice H. Work and Family., 1989 (Box 105, Folder 13)
      Richards Street YWCA. March 22, 1989
    - Cook, Alice H. Work and Family: Bargaining for Family Issues., 1990 (Box 105, Folder 14)
      C/B Seminar. UH/Honolulu. January 11, 1990.
    - Cook, Alice H. Women as an Invisible Minority., 1990 (Box 105, Folder 14)
      Engineering. April 12, 1990.
    - Notes on working women and families (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Cook, Alice H. Can Work Requirements Accommodate to Needs of Dual Earner Families?, 1990 (Box 105, Folder 14)
      World Interdisciplinary Conference. Hunter College, NY. June 5, 1990.
    - Cook, Alice H. History of Employer and Employee Roles in Balancing Work and Family., 1990 (Box 105, Folder 14)
      HumEc Conference. October 23, 1990.
    - Cook, Alice H. Changes at Cornell., 1990 (Box 105, Folder 14)
      Retired Professors. September 24, 1990
    - Cook, Alice H. The Future of the Family., 1990 (Box 105, Folder 14)
      AAUW. Skaneatles. May 5, 1990
    - Cook, Alice H. Pay Equality: Theory and Implementation. Public Personnel Management, 1989 (Box 105, Folder 15)
      December 1, 1989.
    - Cook, Alice H. Bargaining for Support Services., 1989 (Box 105, Folder 15)
      Collective Bargaining Class, UH/IRC. February 14, 1989.
    - Cook, Alice H. Work and Family., 1989 (Box 105, Folder 15)
      YWCA. Honolulu, Hawaii. March 22, 1989.
    - Cook, Alice H. Comparable Worth: What it is and Where We Are, 1989 (Box 105, Folder 15)
      Northwestern University. Boston Massachusetts. April 24, 1989.
    - Cook, Alice H. Gender Equality as a Goal? (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Cook, Alice H. Affirmative Action., 1991 (Box 105, Folder 16)
      The 12th Thelma Lunch: Grad Meeting. December 5, 1991.
    - Cook, Alice H. Address., 1991 (Box 105, Folder 16)
      Rutgers Women's Summer School. June 15, 1991
    - Cook, Alice H. Rose Goldsen: Recollections and Reminders., 1991 (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Cook, Alice H. Women and Work in the World, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 17)
      win/wcb November 19, 1992
    - Cook, Alice H. What are Unions in Other Countries Doing About Women's Leadership in Unions?, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 17)
      Extension Class. NYC. May 5, 1992
    - Cook, Alice H. Women's Health and Safety., 1994 (Box 105, Folder 18)
      For TV Showing. Honolulu Hawaii. March 20, 1994.
    - Cook, Alice H. Unions and Welfare, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 19)
      DSA Meeting. February 15, 1997
    - Outline for a hotel school class, Overview of case studies, Outline about Comparable worth, Notes (Box 105, Folder 20)
    - Cook, Alice H. Problems of Working Mothers; How They are Addressed Throughout the World. (Box 105, Folder 20)
    - Comparable Worth (Box 105, Folder 21)
      Information/speeches, Affirmative Action Information, Collective Bargaining information, Outline of Community Affairs, Outlines
    - Cook, Alice H. Graduation Address. (Box 105, Folder 21)
      June.
    - Cook, Alice H. Working Through Hard Times. (Box 105, Folder 21)
    - Cook, Alice H. Dispute Settlement in Public Employment., 1975 (Box 105, Folder 22)
      Stanford. April 11, 1975.
    - Cook, Alice H. Labor Unions and Gender Problems. (Box 105, Folder 22)
      The Hague. January 21.
    - Undated Speeches by Alice H. Cook (Box 105, Folder 22)
      Nursing School, Labor Relations in the US, Women's Bureau, Sweden, Trade Union Government, Women in the University, Status and Problems of Women, AAUW Workshop, A part Timers Bill of Rights, Women's Issues and the Law, Women and Organizations: the Trade Union, Unionized Labor Force and Union Government, Secretaries Day
  - Sub-Series C. Bibliographic - Card Files (in metal boxes)
    - U.S. (Box 106)
    - Comparative Worth (Box 107)
    - Comp - 2,3; West Germany- 1-2 (Box 108)
    - West Germany- 2-3; US Family- 1-2; Japan- 1-2 (Box 109)
    - Foreign A-Y (Box 110)